<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research | ALICE KATE LI</title>
    <link>https://alicekl.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alicekl.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Research</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alicekl.github.io/media/icon_huf5e2ae4fb7fa7bc920a66551144da9dc_1200_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://alicekl.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Underwater Weather in Rivers</title>
      <link>https://alicekl.github.io/project/underwater_weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicekl.github.io/project/underwater_weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;In a collaborative effort between the &lt;a href=&#34;https://scalar.seas.upenn.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ScalAR Lab&lt;/a&gt; and Penn&amp;rsquo;s Earth and Environmental Science Faculty, Prof. Douglas Jerolmack &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/pennsed/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;(PennSed Group)&lt;/a&gt; and Prof. Hugo N. Ulloa &lt;a href=&#34;https://ge-flow.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;(GEFLOW)&lt;/a&gt;, we leverage autonomous surface vehicles equipped with sensor suites to acquire data about the Schuylkill River.  This work got featured on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/university-of-pennsylvania_using-nature-as-inspiration-laia-mogas-soldevila-activity-7005942802157047808-CL68/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Penn Today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;In acquiring measurements over the same spatial regions over time, gathered data can be used to model spatiotemporal fluid and sediment dynamics in the river. With learnt models, adaptive sampling strategies will be developed to actively determine the most informative sensing locations whilst operating in the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;To further extend work in our recent publication, we are developing a winch to lower sensors into the river, to reconstruct 3D maps of sensor measurements (instead of only surface measurements), and are extending to multi-robot information gathering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Publication&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. K. Li&lt;/strong&gt; et al., &amp;ldquo;Towards Understanding Underwater Weather Events in Rivers Using Autonomous Surface Vehicles,&amp;rdquo; OCEANS 2022, Hampton Roads, Hampton Roads, VA, USA, 2022, pp. 1-8,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9977236?casa_token=mpbJnUwzodIAAAAA:Ic5B2cbHUu44pAvGIf4xIVeW7YqPipi1r8bBNj6_dm71wXBvFUIsTZ9R1RtfkHlcoNbzq-MuAXU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; doi: 10.1109/OCEANS47191.2022.9977236.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Global Dynamics using Koopman Operator Theory</title>
      <link>https://alicekl.github.io/project/koopman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicekl.github.io/project/koopman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Koopman operator theory states that a non-linear dynamical system can be lifted to a higher, and possibly infinite dimensional space, where the dynamics evolve linearly. Given the intractability of this infinite dimension, we develop a framework that approximates a set of finite lifting functions, and the respective Koopman operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Instead of a black-box method, or hand-selecting potential lifting functions, we characterize our lifting functions as Fourier features, and learn the optimal set of Fourier feature parameters (frequencies and phase shift) and Koopman operator for various dynamical systems of varying complexities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Publication&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salam, T., &lt;strong&gt;Li, A. K.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Hsieh, M. A. (2022). Online Estimation of the Koopman Operator Using Fourier Features. &lt;em&gt;Submitted to L4DC. Awaiting Review.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.01503&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; arXiv preprint arXiv:2212.01503.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Information Gathering for Crop Health Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://alicekl.github.io/project/iot4ag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicekl.github.io/project/iot4ag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kumarrobotics.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kumar Lab&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kagan.seas.upenn.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Kagan group&lt;/a&gt; are collaborating to co-design an optical sensor-detector system for measuring crop health. Novel optical agricultural sensors in development by our collaborators shall be scattered onto crop surfaces in their early growth stages. These sensors will directly interface crop surfaces, and continually respond to crop conditions (pH, moisture, etc.), changing color with changes in plant conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;To extract meaningful information from these sensors, we are developing a ground robot with an on board camera to actively localize and classify these sensors, based on a rough estimate of the location of these sensors (as exact sensor locations will change with plant growth). Challenges in this work include (1) variable outdoor lighting conditions; (2) occlusion of sensors from plant foliage; (3) application-based constraints e.g. sensor size, and (4) maneuverability over soil without causing soil compaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
