<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dynamical systems | ALICE KATE LI</title>
    <link>https://alicekl.github.io/tag/dynamical-systems/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alicekl.github.io/tag/dynamical-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>dynamical systems</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alicekl.github.io/media/icon_huf5e2ae4fb7fa7bc920a66551144da9dc_1200_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>dynamical systems</title>
      <link>https://alicekl.github.io/tag/dynamical-systems/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>(RA-L 2024) EnKode - Active learning of flows with Koopman operators</title>
      <link>https://alicekl.github.io/project/enkode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicekl.github.io/project/enkode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Koopman operator theory can be used to provide a functional form of the flow of nonlinear dynamical systems, as well as physically interpretable feature extraction in the form of coherent sets. Both are valuable for downstream robotics tasks such as path planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;However, collecting data to build these models is expensive.
Therefore, in this work, we propose EnKode, a method based on Koopman theory and ensemble methods that models flows and provides an active sensing strategy to guide robots to collect sparse informative data for the flow model. From our knowledge, it is the first works to apply Koopman theory to the task of robotic active sensing and modeling of flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;In evaluating our methods on three flows of increasing complexities, including real ocean flows, we show that EnKode provides high quality uncertainty quantification in comparison to a Gaussian Process regression model baseline; multi-scale modeling capabilities; and an effective active sensing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Publication&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Li, Alice K.&lt;/strong&gt;, Thales C. Silva, and M. Ani Hsieh. &amp;ldquo;EnKode: Active Learning of Unknown Flows with Koopman Operators.&amp;rdquo; &lt;i&gt; IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (2024). &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;u&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/10733989&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Link to paper. &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(L4DC 2023) Learning Global Dynamics using Koopman Operator Theory</title>
      <link>https://alicekl.github.io/project/koopman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alicekl.github.io/project/koopman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Koopman operator theory states that a non-linear dynamical system can be lifted to a higher, and possibly infinite dimensional space, where the dynamics evolve linearly. Given the intractability of this infinite dimension, we develop a framework that approximates a finite set of lifting functions that linearize the system, and the respective Koopman operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Instead of a black-box method, or hand-selecting potential lifting functions, we characterize our lifting functions as Fourier features, and learn the optimal set of Fourier feature parameters (frequencies and phase shift) and Koopman operator for various dynamical systems of varying complexities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Publication&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;Salam, Tahiya, &lt;strong&gt;Alice Kate Li&lt;/strong&gt;, and M. Ani Hsieh. &amp;ldquo;Online Estimation of the Koopman Operator Using Fourier Features.&amp;rdquo; &lt;i&gt; Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference. PMLR, 2023. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;u&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://proceedings.mlr.press/v211/salam23a.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Link to paper.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
